Zoya Matsiy DataAnalyst

Milan, Italy +39 345-322-1343 zoyany39@gmail.com LinkedIn Tableau Public Github

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A motivated and team-work-oriented analyst with 10+ years of experience in the Wholesale Trade, Tourism, and Real Estate Sector and 20+ years of relevant experience. Specializing in transforming raw big-size data into valuable information through reports and presentations to support data-driven decision-making and marketing and sales strategy definition.

SKILLS

- Business Analytics
- Excel ninja
- Data visualization with **Tableau**
- PostgreSQL
- **Python** libraries and dashboards (NumPy, Pandas, SciPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, Scikit-Learn)
- Statistical and predictive analysis, Data modeling (**ARIMA model**), and forecasting
- Google Analytics and SEO
- Google Ads, Facebook Ads
- HTML and CSS

COMPETENCES

- Self-starter
- Accuracy and attention to detail
- Critical and creative thinking
- Presentation skills
- Stakeholder comunication
- Constant learner with a steep learning curve
- Effective **problem-solving** abilities
- Domain knowledge in **finance**, **healthcare**, **e-commerce**, wholesale

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Data Analytics Program

2024 - Career Foundry GmbH, Berlin, Germany

MTSM - Master of Tourism Sales Management

2014 - Bicocca University, Milan, Italy

MBA- Master of Business Administration

2000 - Otto von Guerike University, Magdeburg, Germany

Bachelor's degree in chemical engineering

1995 – Moscow State University, Moscow, Russia

LANGUAGES

English – C1, Italian – C1, Russian -C2 (native), German – C1

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst/ MC immobiliare di Carrus (Milam, Italy)

Settembre 2018 - February 2020

Achievement: Thanks to regular reporting to stakeholders, increasing customer loyalty to 8%

- Build a **financial model** tailored to different real estate markets.
- Supportet customers **creating blueprints** of real estate investments with requested financial metrics

Business Consultant/4U Service (Milan, Italy)

July 2017 - Settembre 2018

Achievement: IT Company **diversification support**. Diversification completed in 4 months.

- Provided Business Data Analytics for diversification strategy definition.
- Created a **Marketing plan** of diversification and supported its realization.
- Provided Business Analytics for critical clients to continue collaboration. 98% of the customers remained after diversification, with 10% of customers growing after six months.

Business Data Analyst/Suend di TSM Tourism & Services Management srl (Milan, Italy)

June 2016 - July 2017

Achievement: The 20% expansion of the geographical area of tourism services thanks to creating the new relational database.

- Collect data and create a regional customers and accommodation services relational database (Eastern Europe).
- Regular Data Analytic reporting of the actual market situation, KPI tracking panel for providing services.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Director of Business Development/ Elkotex OAO (Moscow, Russia)

February 2001 – June 2012

Achievement: Thanks to data-driven decision-making, the total revenue of the enterprise increased by 22%. An effective sales team was created, and a new warehouse management system based on the new CRM was implemented. The system of regular reporting on a KPI basis was introduced.

- Total cost of wholesale textiles decreased by 5%.
- Total revenue of wholesale textiles increased by 8%
- The wholesale assortment changed by 32%, the total assortment increased by 57%
- The warehouse balances have been destroyed by 24%